- Going, in, I know there was
a little bit of a behind schedule.
Good after, is it afternoon? Yes.
It's not morning anymore. Good afternoon, everyone.
Thank you for joining us today
for this important conversation
on Preparing Our Students for the Future.
My name is Alicia Cardenas.
I am a counselor at West Valley College
in Saratoga, California,
and I am also working with the State Chancellor's Office
as an AI Fellow with Student Support Services.
I'm excited to welcome our panelists,
Tara, from Ourmedia,
Christian from AI Education Project,
and Summer from Skillfully,
who bring value perspectives
from education industry and workforce development.
I've recently connected with all three
to learn more about their innovative approaches
and helping prepare students for an AI-driven world.
Some of the framework for today is this panel will explore
how community colleges can bring classroom learning
to work with workforce demands
in an era transformed by AI.
Skills landscape and employer demands are changing rapidly
in the advent of AI requiring a lot of new tools
and foundation, AI fluency and literacy,
and also preparing new opportunities for AI tools
to upskill our community college students in the workforce
and in industry demand skills.
Featuring again, our leaders from Ourmedia,
AI Education Projects, Skillfully,
the conversation will highlight
how AI is reshaping student experiences
and surfacing and differentiated skills
and exposing workforce gaps.
Throughout the spotlight presentations
and dynamic discussion,
panelists will examine how educators,
employers, and policy makers can align
around AI skill building, scale system solutions,
and ensure equitable opportunities
for economic advancement and growth.
Let's begin this important conversation
about empowering our students with AI skills
that they need for this economic advancement.
So here goes the first question for everyone.
Each of you,
"For your organizations partnering
with California Community Colleges
to embed AI within our ecosystem,
could you share more about your organization
and how you've currently been working
to uplevel AI exposure with our system?"
- Yeah, I have a brief presentation,
so I'm gonna jump right over here.
All right. Everyone can hear me all right?
Awesome. Hi guys, my name's Tara.
It's nice to meet you all.
I'm the Associate Director of Ourmedia.
And it works. Cool.
I had not tried the button yet.
And I'm excited to spend a couple minutes sharing
a little bit about the way that we're working
with California's community colleges to lead the way
when it comes to student-centered AI engagement.
So first, I just wanted to start by digging a little bit
into the problem that we're looking at right now.
At Ourmedia,
we really see three kind of core intersecting issues
that we're responding to.
The first one is that AI will have really significant
but uncertain impacts on young people's transition
from learning into career.
The second piece is that we currently don't really have
a mechanism in the traditional educational model to,
in real time, dig deep with the students and ask them,
"What do you need when it comes to the way
that this technology is changing
what it looks like for you to learn and enter career?"
The last piece is the one that I find most concerning,
which is that right now when we look
at AI integration, AI adoption,
and just conversations around AI
in really well-resourced kind of elite university spaces,
students are getting really hands-on experiences
working with AI.
They're getting introductions to AI ethics
and things like that,
and we just don't necessarily yet have
a comprehensive and kinda consistent approach
at the community college level.
And so Ourmedia's whole mission is to empower young people
to thrive in an AI-driven future of work.
And what our approach looks like in that is
co-designing participatory research with Gen Z.
So we're turning student insights
into institutional recommendations.
I thought that was a fun little, yeah.
I'm glad you guys liked it as well. (chuckles)
It brought me so much excitement
and hope this morning to hear Dr. Christian talk
so much about that kind of student-centered strategy.
So yeah, I just wanna dig in a little more
and share what that has looked like for us.
So what we're currently trying to build
and eventually scale is a way to host workshops
with students that basically give them specific scenarios
about the way that they might interact
with AI in the classroom,
but then in the job search
and then all the way into their first job.
So we're saying things like, for example,
if you know AI might show up
at some part of the interview process,
do you feel prepared to navigate that situation?
What are you excited about or curious about it?
On the flip side,
are you afraid of anything or anxious about that situation?
And the whole kind of focus with these workshops is,
one, to give students that first look into, oh, wow,
AI is gonna impact not just my learning,
but the entire transition I'm gonna make into the workforce.
And then two, we're trying to surface all of those really,
really rich data insights from the students
that give us cues as to, okay,
here are their core gaps in understanding,
here are the skills and experiences
that are gonna make them successful
in this AI-driven future of work.
So that first piece, student-centered listening
is at the heart of everything that we do.
That second piece,
we listen to the students surface those insights,
and then we bring them right into conversation with faculty.
So an example of what this has looked like,
and I'll share a QR code
to check out a report we put out recently,
but this past spring we worked
with some of the community colleges
down in Orange County and we hosted that listening workshop
I had mentioned to students.
And then in the afternoon,
we hosted a session with faculty and we said,
"Okay, if these are what the students are saying they need,
these are the consistent questions they're asking,
how might that influence
or kinda change your thinking in the classroom?"
That third piece is that we're trying to develop a model
that is scalable so that eventually, you know,
right now it looks like us coming
onto a campus hosting this workshop.
Eventually we wanna put together a toolkit
so that the 116 campuses across the system are gonna be
empowered to be able to do this kind of listening
with their students on their own and then act on it.
That's that QR code that I had mentioned right there.
So like I had said,
we did some work down in Orange County this past spring.
It was a really, really wonderful group of students
and faculty and leaders that we worked with.
And I wanna share, you know,
one of the core perspectives that really stood out to me
was AI should support, not replace our learning.
We want help, not shortcuts.
So that's something that I was excited to hear
and I would really encourage you all
to check out that report.
And then looking ahead, as I had mentioned,
we're in that phase of refining the workshop
and we eventually want to scale it and offer a toolkit.
The California Community College is,
it's a massive system
and all of the different regions have different needs.
So this is the time where I'd really invite you all
to reach out to me and be part of this co-creation process.
We wanna make sure that the workshop model we're developing
matters just as much to rural colleges in NorCal
as they do to the ones in LA County.
You know, and that means
that we need everyone's voice at this stage.
So if you're interested in seeing this kind of work
being offered to your students
or having a voice in this,
I would really encourage you guys, reach out and email me.
It's right up there,
or come find me at the end of the session.
Yeah, so thank you all.
(audience clapping)
- Next, we'll hear from Christian.
And our aid, let me see.
- Amazing, so I will spend a little bit of time
to introduce myself as well.
First of all, I recognize it's cold.
Thank you all for being here. (audience laughing)
I am cold as well.
Okay, so as mentioned, my name is Christian. Hi, everybody.
I work with AI Education Project or aiEDU for short.
We are a nonprofit organization that works nationally,
primarily with K-12 school districts
to pursue work in light of AI readiness.
Essentially, we partner with school districts,
in some cases county offices of education,
in some cases state departments of education,
in some cases higher education organizations.
Our goal is really to equip teachers,
K-12 systems, and students ultimately
for the skills, capacities,
mindsets that they need to thrive in the world
where AI is quite ubiquitous.
And I know it's like a probably a point
that you've all heard several times in the past day,
but the work that we do is really
to go hand-in-hand with school systems.
I try and talk about our work
in like three primary pillars of work.
The first is defining like,
what the heck does AI readiness even mean?
I know there's a ton of conversations around
like what skills and capacities students need
in order to thrive in this AI world.
We do, yes, define those skills and capacities,
but we try and actually like tease that a little bit more.
We deliver a lot of this transformative work.
So that can range from content development,
that ranges from policy development,
teacher training, guidance, research reports.
We do a lot of that work itself.
And then we also try and catalyze this movement.
We issue grants out to other nonprofit organizations.
We partner with other national movements.
We work with state agencies and governmental bodies
in order to make sure the work is scaled and equitable.
Generally, we try and work deeply within a few states.
We know that as one small national nonprofit organization,
we're about 20 people right now,
we can't work everywhere in as deep as we'd want to,
so we'd rather scale depth rather than scale breadth.
And so we've chosen a few specific states
to do some work in, California, being one of them.
I'm based in California. I was a California teacher.
I love the state so much.
And so like doing a lot of work here is something
that we're really, really dedicated to.
So as we define what AI readiness means, this is what I'm,
like the core of what we think of AI readiness is
and how it's differentiated from AI literacy is
we think of AI literacy as like understanding the basics
of how AI works using AI tools, yada yada.
But we do think that it needs
to be paired with other basic things
that aren't usually defined under AI literacy,
like being a critical thinker, being self-motivated,
being creative, being collaborative.
Those aren't necessary AI literacy skills,
but we do think those are necessary skills
in order for students to be able to thrive in a world
where AI is quite ubiquitous.
And so we also wanna pair that with something that we refer
to as a human advantage and students understanding
and implicitly knowing how to leverage
their human advantage skills in this economy
that's gonna be very disrupted
by technology in the next couple of years
and has already seen that disruption happening.
And we lay out this framework not just for students,
but we also do all of this depth of work for educators.
What do educators and what skills do educators need
to be equipped with?
And then what do systems,
like what are actual the systemic mechanisms
to make this available to all teachers
and all educators and students within that system?
And so we try and lay out this framework
from a individual perspective
scaled up to what the system needs to do
in order to support that individual.
And like I said, we develop a lot of classroom curricula,
we do a lot of teacher professional development.
I know this is probably the change mechanism
that's very difficult to scale within school systems
is how do I upskill my current educators?
How do we make sure that the people working within my system
are able to actually work with this disruption
and are not getting overwhelmed by it?
Investing in the human capital
that you have in your system is probably the first step
that you need to make before you start investing
in the tech capacities within these new systems.
If you do one without the other,
then it's just not gonna work,
making sure that both are paired
with an actual like order of operations
that makes sense and it includes teacher buy-in
is so critical.
And like I said,
we do a lot of work directly with school systems.
It ranges from small K-12 school districts
to the entire state Departments of Education.
Understanding how this works from a big school system
like New York City public schools
down to a small rural district in Northern California,
like understanding what change management looks like
in these different systems is really important to us
to understand that like there is no-one-size-fits-all model
for AI readiness in all these systems.
And then, like I said, we try and catalyze our work,
meaning we develop partnerships, we do research,
we issue a lot of grants.
I think so far we've issued
about $2.5 million in grants to small,
specifically rural and Indigenous nonprofits
across the country
to do this work themselves within their own communities
to make sure that this is something that is built
out of communities and not put into communities.
And a lot of the work that we're doing
with the California Community College system
is in service of this mission.
We wanna make sure that we are good partners in this space,
that we are not trying to own the work.
Everything that we develop,
everything that we put out is licensed
through Creative Commons, everything is open source.
We really want to be a good partner
and a catalyst for this change
and human-centered change for that matter.
And so we establish these partnerships
in order to make sure that students
are on a path to AI readiness,
and that necessitates systemic readiness,
that necessitates educator readiness itself.
And it cannot just be something that's a tool
and a technology tool that you implement right away
and you say, the AI box is checked off.
We're gonna make sure that we're actually addressing
systemic change that needs to be addressed.
So thank you and we'll get into discussion
a little bit later.
(audience clapping)
- Next is Summer from Skillfully.
- Hello, everyone and good afternoon.
As Alicia mentioned,
my name is Summer
and I'm the Head of Partnerships at Skillfully
and I'm really excited to share
some of the exciting work
that we're doing with a number of colleges
within the California Community College ecosystem.
Really the north star of Skillfully
is to enhance students' career opportunities
through experiential learning and work integrated learning.
And I'll tell you a little bit about how we do this
and I'll try to keep this concise.
So we're an AI platform
that is basically enabling a digital twin
of the skills that you see reflected
in the ever evolving skills landscape
within the industry today.
What we're able to do and offer students
is the ability to use our AI tooling
to build out simulations
that are a direct representation of a particular job
or a particular suite of industry skills
basically allowing that experiential learning
for those particular skills
to enable career readiness for students.
Students are, through our platform,
able to not just showcase their skills through a resume,
but also often or more often,
so through the actual skills demonstrations
through our simulations, which are scored
and they're provided feedback and evaluation on.
Our simulations also enable deeper career exploration.
So when a student is deciding, hey is, you know,
am I interested in a career in sales or healthcare,
it's hard to be able to know whether that's true
unless they have actually had their hand in trying it.
So what our simulations enable is a lever
by which students can get exposure
to these skills throughout their educational journey
to see if a particular career trajectory
is of actual interest to them.
Our platform also delivers broader,
overarching career readiness support
in the form of wraparound interviewing,
mentorship and networking support as well.
And as I mentioned,
all of these simulations are scored
and we're giving narrative feedback to students
so they could actually uplevel their skill proficiencies
within both of these industry-specific skills domains
in addition to the broader career skills
that they'll need to succeed.
I wanna talk a little bit about an interesting pilot
that we're doing
with the Bay Area Community College Consortium.
We're really excited about this work
and are excited to expand this work in the coming semesters.
Currently we are working with some local
big tech players, namely companies like Salesforce,
to be able to take their job descriptions
for their entry-level roles.
We're doing a specific emphasis
on tech sales roles right now
and we are building out digital twins
of those job descriptions
to put those in front of students for two purposes.
One, skill development and skill exposure.
And also for us to be able to validate
and evaluate those students
for opportunities for actual apprenticeship
or full-time opportunities that those employers might have.
As I mentioned,
we want to make sure that we're democratizing access
to not just the students who might be applying
within that particular program
or within that particular hiring cycle.
So we make these available to a number
of the different colleges across the BACCC ecosystem
so that students can practice these skill simulations
and get that feedback that they need
to be able to further develop these skills
for future career opportunities.
Some future directions that we're exploring for this work.
We'd like to expand outside of just this tech sales hub
to other industries like healthcare.
Also looking at computer science careers as well.
And also, as my friends on stage today,
looking at enabling AI literacy and fluency
for students across the California College ecosystem.
I think my five minutes is up.
Thank you for your patience there
and if you're interested in working with us,
I put my email address up on the screen here.
Also, I'll be hanging out a little bit
after this presentation,
so feel free to come and talk to me.
All right, thank you so much.
(audience clapping)
- Thank you, everybody.
We're gonna go ahead and ask the panelists questions
starting off with Tara from Ourmedia.
"So your work at Ourmedia centers on partnering with Gen Z
to identify AI literacy and career readiness needs
and use cases in order to inform faculty
and administrative responses to AI's impact
on learning and career environment.
How should students' attitudes inform
the development of responses to AI
in the learning and career?"
- Thank you.
Well, I mean,
I'll start by sharing my opinion
that student voices should be involved
at every level of learning design, but...
Oh, thank you. I'm like, you can clap for that. (laughs)
(audience laughing)
But I think that AI specifically introduces
really chaos, honestly,
introduces chaos to the traditional learning model
in ways that really, really kind of increase
the need to right now be digging in
with the students directly.
One statistic I saw recently that just kind of blew me away,
I think it was from, I wanna say the World Economic Forum,
was that 49% of Gen Zs who had been surveyed
who'd recently attained a degree
reported feeling that what they were seeing around them
with AI meant that their degree had less value.
So I think one really fundamental question
that's being asked right now in just across
a lot of higher ed spaces is what are the skills
that young people need to be equipped with
to succeed in this AI-driven future of work?
And then how are we as institutions equipping
them with those skills?
I think that starting with student attitudes
to then find practical solutions
that can support them is the way to go
because when students are expressing fear or anxiety
or on the flip side curiosity or excitement,
those are really important cues that tell us, okay,
here are potentially really important needs that they have
or here area areas that they just don't have
any comfort or familiarity in.
So maybe this is where we need
to beef up the support that we're giving.
So yeah, all of that to say,
I think it's always important
to look at student attitudes to get cues when we're dealing
with something that's as transformative as AI,
but especially right now as we're seeing
that like the career ladder
is gonna be chopped off at the bottom,
entry level roles are gonna be
potentially going away in a lot of spaces.
And so we need to sit down
and all of these questions that were
on this side of education
asking the students are asking them too.
And I think starting that dialogue
is the best way to move forward.
- Christian, "Your work at the AI Education Project
centers on providing educators
with the tools they need to help students thrive
in a world where AI is everywhere.
What are the biggest challenges that educators are facing
in ensuring their students are AI proficient?"
- I mean, as I mentioned,
the majority of my work is with K-12 systems,
and I can tell you right off the bat that
teachers in K-12 systems don't see a lot of support
coming from the system itself or them,
and AI looks very different depending
on the students that they're serving,
meaning what a third grade teacher is experiencing
is gonna be extremely different
from what a 10th grade teacher is gonna be experiencing
and there is no solution that will work
for both of those teachers.
And school systems are right now
are having a hard time understanding
what those support systems need to look like,
what teachers actually are needing.
Concurrently, and this is something I'm sure
all of you can agree with,
is we see a lot of a push from EdTech.
Like, I am making assumptions here,
but I'm assuming the marketing budgets
for a lot of EdTech companies has gone up substantially
because at the same time we see teachers being marketed
to by a lot of EdTech tools, platforms,
websites that are AI powered
and there's a lot of noise out there
in terms of what a solution can look like
or what a solution should be.
And so with all of that noise
and with all of the disruption that's happening
both to students and teachers in their personal lives
and in their professional lives,
I think teachers are kind of like,
either putting their head in the sand
because navigating this world is a little bit too much
and they're already a little bit overworked
and/or they're looking for the one thing
that will save them time or the one thing
that they think is gonna be the silver bullet.
And that's where a lot
of these marketing campaigns are working.
And that's what you see adoption for AI tools
so broad is because there are real needs out there
that teachers are experiencing.
And a lot of times AI tools can
promise solutions to those needs.
I think this idea of offloading
a solutions to those needs from the system
to individual tools is something I don't want to see.
Something I would love to see more of is like,
how can systems support teachers a little bit more directly?
How can systems offer those resources,
those, I guess, like guidance to help cut through noise?
I don't need another 50-page report.
I need like a two-page,
like really quick thing about what I need to do right now
in the next semester of my work
in order to actually address student readiness.
And the next semester,
what are the next few things that our system
is working on that I need to implement now?
I think making it bite-sized,
making it immediately actionable
and making support actually responsive to teacher needs
is something that's really, really necessary right now.
- Question is for Summer. Let's see.
I'm sorry, lemme get...
"While Ourmedia and the AI Education Project
are providing tools for AI literacy to students,
Skillfully provides AI-driven technology
to ensure that students and job seekers
are ready for the workforce.
At a time when the skills employers demands
are changing rapidly,
how can we make sure higher ed is staying
in step with changing industry skills?
What are employers looking for as skills change?"
- Thank you for that question, Alicia,
and I'll tackle the first portion of that question
just around the rapidly changing skills landscape
that's happening out in the job market today.
My colleagues have talked a lot
about how AI is disrupting the skills landscape
and how things are rapidly changing,
wiping out entry level roles.
And in addition,
we also have employers who are turning
to more skills-based hiring approaches
where they're really trying to make sure
there's a precise match between a student
or a job seeker skills and what they're hiring for.
So the question of how do we make sure
that higher ed is able to stay in parallel
or in step with those employer demands,
which ultimately, whether we like it or not,
those are the arbiters
of who ultimately does enter the workforce.
We just need to have more collaboration
between employers and higher ed.
And I know that I'm preaching to the choir, (laughs)
so I know that this is not like a profound statement.
I can share a little bit about some of the work
that we're doing with other partners
where we're bringing employers to the table
to be active participants and helping to relay
and translate how skills are changing in the workforce
so that we can then translate that in the form
of our technology to the students, job seekers,
and learners that we're working in our partnerships
with workforce development organizations, higher ed,
and in some cases K-12 CTE programming.
I wish I had like a silver bullet to say it's like easy,
but a lot of this is like starting from the ground up,
re-imagining what's possible,
having multiple conversations
with employer and industry partners
to help translate that skills data.
And then making sure as ed tech providers
we're actually being responsive to that.
Not just like putting something shiny
and flashy out there for the sake of marketing, but like,
we are solving a real problem
and helping us to bridge this skills gap
and this chasm that's widening
and even more rapidly than it was say,
you know, five years ago.
And, sorry,
I think there was one more piece of that question
around what skills
are employers looking for? - Yes.
- While we have done a lot of work on making sure
that we are bridging those skills for the, you know,
industry-relevant or role-specific skills
that employers are looking for,
a huge thing that we hear from both the, you know,
our career service partners
and from the employers that we work with is
we can't leave the durable skills behind, right?
So we have to make sure that when students are showing up
for interviews, they're able to hold eye contact,
they're able to articulate their transferable skills
that they've gathered throughout their career
or through their, you know, past lived experiences.
And so I just wanna make sure
that we're not just focusing on, okay,
these industry skills are changing
or this is what you now need to be successful
in this particular role in the sector.
But also just making sure we're really helping to uplevel
and maintain those critical durable skills as well
for students and job seekers.
- Thank you. Back to Tara from Ourmedia.
"What insights have you gathered from students
regarding Ourmedia's recent report
piloting students-centered AI engagement
across California Community Colleges?"
- Yeah, so I mean, I think,
I'll offer a statement and offer a few themes.
The statement would be
that there is no one consistent student perspective
or relationship with AI.
I've interacted over the past couple of years
with students who say, "I will never ever touch AI
no matter how you offer it to me."
And I've talked to other students who are saying,
"I don't know how I would've learned without AI."
And there's a wide spectrum in between those.
So that's kind of the overall thing.
But then within that, there is some themes
that I've definitely been noticing recently
and a lot of them are reflected in the...
So to drill in a little more
into what the spring effort looked like,
we hosted that workshop with students.
We also hosted a panel of student leaders
as well as doing some student interviews.
So we got a really kind of holistic view
of the student perspective.
One really big theme that stood out to me
is that a lot of students were saying,
"I'm really concerned about AI's impacts
on my critical thinking skills.
I'm really concerned that I'm gonna develop a dependency
on AI that makes it hard for me to be creative or efficient
or collaborative on my own."
Some students were saying, "I see this with my own self."
One quote that came to me from a student,
actually not in the spring,
but even before that was, "When I use AI,
sometimes it feels like I'm turning my brain off."
That was definitely concerning.
Some of them are saying, "When I look around at my peers,
I'm worried that they're relying on tools
that I'm not relying on,
and they're not gonna be able to keep up
with me when it really comes down
to actually doing the work."
So that's the first thing is really, really concerned about
where is the boundary for how much
and to what extent I should be engaging with AI.
The second theme that stood out to me was,
how is AI gonna change
what it looks like for me to get a job?
I think that's the biggest fear that students have
'cause they're seeing the headlines.
There are massive layoffs in the tech industry,
but elsewhere, I think I saw something
that said that two-thirds of hiring managers say
that they wouldn't consider hiring someone
who's not AI literate.
So the students are hearing these headlines and the signals
and they're concerned.
They're like, "I know this will impact
my ability to get a job."
The third piece, after those first two,
is that students don't seem to have a consistent narrative
coming to them from their educators
about how to deal with those first two pieces.
So when it comes to making sure
that they're not developing over reliance on AI
or on the flip side, if they're trying to prepare
to succeed in the future of work,
a really, really common concern that I heard was,
"Some of my professors are saying to use it,
some of them aren't.
And I don't know how to make sense of all of this."
So I think that's at the heart of what we're trying
to do with our approach
of bringing the student voices into dialogue with faculty
and administrators is to make sure that
from the educator perspective, we're well equipped
with hear how my students are engaging with AI,
hear what their needs ares, hear what their fears are,
and here's how I deliver a consistent message
that helps them deal with that.
So yeah, I feel like I talked for a while, but.
- Thank you.
Next question here for Christian,
from the AI Education Project,
"Where are you seeing the most success in working
with educators to embed AI literacy into their curriculum?"
- This one working? - Yes.
- Cool, this mic is really cute, so I'll use this one.
So the thing about AI literacy work
is that you don't want it to feel like an extra thing
that educators have to do
'cause I think educator's workloads
and the objectives that they have in their courses
and their curricula is already quite overloaded.
And so the most success
that you have in helping educators actually build
student AI literacy is in the opportunities you have
to embed those learning objectives
in already existing learning objectives.
And I like to reference this a lot,
it's quite akin to the internet, where the internet
is something that's quite ubiquitous,
it's changed to work,
it's really disrupted a lot of industries.
In your courses, in your classes,
we don't have internet learning objectives
that are siloed into like an internet category.
Similarly, I don't think we need AI learning objectives
that are siloed into an AI category.
Like we embed internet literacy work naturally
because it's a part of the way that we work,
it's a part of the way that we share information,
it's a part of the way that we even learn today
in the real world.
I think the same thing's gonna happen with AI.
We need to embed AI literacy into the existing work streams
that are happening.
If in classes teachers are pursuing
project-based learning opportunities,
how can you embed the use of AI tools
in those learning opportunities to embed AI literacy
as part of one of those learning objectives?
Even though it might be a project on world languages,
you could still think about how students can use
or think about AI as it pertains to that project itself.
And so I would say the most success is when teachers
don't feel like AI is something that's like put onto them
as an additional layer that's on a stack of objectives
that they already have to teach against.
But when it's a part or embedded
within already existing learning objectives,
it is not gonna take extra time out of their classroom
or out of their syllabus,
it's not gonna take extra units
of lesson planning and delivery.
I think that's where you can do it.
And to be honest, it's a lot easier than it might feel.
AI as a technology is novel, it's new,
but it's still very embedded
in everyday things that we do day-to-day.
Not every example of AI
is a large language model chatbot interface.
There's plenty of examples of AI being embedded
in maybe more background things
that you're engaging with every day.
So as you're teaching from subjects like history,
art, ELA, math, whatever it could be,
I think teaching about data sets, teaching about
like technology platforms, teaching about
how AI is influencing the real world is something
that is a lot easier to embed that you might think.
It just takes a, I think, a lens of thinking about
that embedding work or us to make it happen.
I wanna make sure that the message coming from a system
to an educator is not that AI is another siloed subject
that you need to be teaching in your coursework,
but rather it's something that should be embedded
and like let's help these educators embed this
into their existing coursework.
And I think that's where you're gonna find the most success
into making sure that your students are prepared
like in this next semester or two, not in three semesters
after we've redesigned entire courses.
- Thank you. Next question here for Summer from Skillfully.
"How can AI be used to ensure that students
are working ready or work ready
and be placed into high potential careers
after leaving the system?"
- Thank you for that question.
We've talked a lot about the,
or AI's disruption
and the uncertainty that that creates for higher ed.
Simultaneously, there is a huge opportunity for AI
to act as a lever to democratize access
to all students for both career skill building
and career exposure.
I guess I'll go back to just
my big plug for just trying to, as much as we possibly can,
embed experiential learning and work integrated learning
into not only the classroom
but also at the career services level.
We think that the intersection of that philosophy
and that approach with AI creates a huge opportunity
for students to get both role specific upskilling
that's gonna be required for them
to be successful in today's job market.
AI also allows us to more flexibly
and scalably prop up those kind of micro internship
or virtual internship opportunities to keep pace
with the evolving nature of the skills landscape.
And it also just offers an opportunity for us
to be able to offer broader career skill building
and development to students.
Whether that's getting prepared for an interview,
whether that's practicing a mentorship
or a networking chat to do an informational interview
with a mentor or someone whose career
you might be interested learning more about.
That's where we feel like there's a really big
and powerful opportunity for AI to be
a really powerful tool in helping students
to be become more workplace ready.
So, not to say that there are not challenges with that.
I think this disruption
and the pace at which it's happened has,
I imagine has created large scale challenges
for you all as educators.
But on the flip side of that,
I think there also is a huge opportunity
to help support your students as well.
- I'm gonna jump in a little bit actually on like...
So Skillfully, the way that you talk about this
is I think very akin to like the real world jobs market.
I think something that education
and like the jobs market oftentimes misconstrue
is you're actually doing a lot of the same things,
but you're just speaking two very different languages.
If you look at economists report
and research that comes out of economists
and like output that comes out of education research,
a lot of times they're the same things.
I think you talk about like skills-based workforce,
in education, we just call those learning objectives
and like they do map to skills,
but we don't do that mapping
in the same way the workforce does.
And so as much as you can,
think about how learning objectives that you have
for students might map to skills
and like taking that skills landscape
and mapping it to what skills you think are gonna be most
effective in the workforce,
like that is a gap that I think exists between education
and economy that hasn't quite been closed
or is like, like I said,
it's like speaking two different languages.
But as much as we can kind of map the learning objectives
to actual workplace skills like what you're talking about,
I think our mechanisms for updating education
to be more effective for the real world
are gonna be much more clear than you think they are.
- Thank you, so as we wrap up this session,
wanna just bring a few points for each of our presenters.
Ourmedia talked about empowering young people
using a hands-on approach, preparing, you know,
for AI through workshops using the Train the Trainer model
to educate and they host workshops at campuses.
The AI Education Project talked about content,
policy development, working closely with K-12,
framework for students and educators,
classroom curriculum, webinars, they offer that as well.
Skillfully talked about experiential learning,
offers AI platform that allows students
to use simulated opportunities for career readiness.
Students are provided feedback
from these AI-simulated platforms
so they can improve their skills.
Here's some questions that I just wanna leave for thinking:
How are institutions equipping our students?
How can we get our students, you know,
with solving problems, having them, you know,
be creative with innovative skills?
How can the opportunity
of experiential learning opportunities be offered?
And how can we embed, as Christian said,
how can we embed AI literacy
into student learning outcomes?
So now what we'll do is we'll open the floor for questions
for any of our presenters
or each of our presenters can maybe answer the question.
Yes. - [Attendee] My question is,
when we're working to support students in connecting with
understanding employers in our local are looking for,
and we're creating these events where
that allows that interface,
not only in a panel discussion
but in a networking environment.
What is the best way to convey to students
what an amazing opportunity that is, you know,
in a way that (indistinct), "I've gotta be there," right?
Do you have any suggestions for that?
- I mean there's, I think students,
I mean you'll know this more about this from like your work
with like listening to student voice,
but I do think students feel inherently this anxiety
about the shifting jobs landscape.
I do think that there is a lot of uncertainty.
Even if you ask these companies
how they're shifting hiring practices
or how they're shifting skills assessments.
Even these companies are still in the middle
of figuring that out themselves.
Like large corporations are still doing that,
let alone smaller local businesses as well.
And so having direct connection
or direct line to these local businesses
is probably the best way that you can hear
about what's happening in real time.
I think there's probably a little bit of comfort
that might come from that connection point
between student and local business
to understand that shifting landscape.
Because what students are probably going to hear
is that local businesses are also wanting to figure it out.
Local businesses are actually probably gonna
want to know the student perspective as well.
Like as an early as a worker
or as someone who's coming into the workforce,
what are things that you think are gonna change?
What are skills that you bring to the table
that maybe some of my older employees
don't bring to the table?
I think having that discussion or starting that
is going to quell anxieties
from both the employer and the employees.
And I think emphasizing that point
is gonna be really helpful.
- I'm gonna steal your mic.
I think mine wasn't quite working.
I think that's a really great question
just around the student engagement piece.
So candidly, like we've set up programs in the past
for learners where, you know, it's a self to opt-in
type of thing and we see super low engagement
'cause I think the reality
and the nature of students' lives is that
some of them may have families, they're very busy,
they're competing priorities, they might have multiple jobs.
I think one of the ways that we have been trying to solve
for this is as skillfully is collecting
kind of the industry requirements
or asks for these skills of like,
"Hey, it would be really great if, you know,
aside from the technical skills
that we can teach people on the job,
if they could just show up with proactivity problem solving,
we're able to then bake that into special programs
that we can deliver to students through our platform
that are, we hope in best case scenario,
anchored to some type of specific program
within the college, some type of special initiative.
And that's where we've really started
to see like we pique students' interest
and it really helps to guide that engagement,
despite the multiple competing priorities
that they might have going on in their lives.
And so I think we, you know, as ed tech platforms,
as educators, we have a responsibility to just make sure
that we're putting that information
in front of students in a way that's going to align
with the structures of their lives
and the reality of their lived experience.
And I do think that AI and technology
is a lever in helping us to do
that a little bit more efficiently.
- Yeah, first kudos to you,
'cause that sounds like a really,
really wonderful opportunity for the students.
Like networking I think is one of the core skills right now
that young people need to be developing.
Networking, connecting to mentors,
and then those kind of job experiences.
My recommendation might be to try
and find some success stories
and put that in front of the students.
My experience has been
that you can tell a student 7 million times
that this will help them.
It's way more impactful for another student to come in
and say, "I was skeptical too.
I took the time to participate
and here are the opportunities that came out of it."
That's really the kind of thing
that'll make them wake up to it.
And if there's no students who could speak to that,
even just someone on your team who could say,
"I get it, you're overwhelmed and you're busy,
but here's what it looked like for me
to put myself out like that.
And here's what came of it."
- Yes. - So information age created
this whole population of disenfranchised workers,
and many of us are concerned about AI
creating another population of disenfranchised workers.
Each of you really, particularly Tara and Christian,
are focused on a traditionally age students
like (indistinct) audience.
Christian and Tara, have you chosen (indistinct).
What about the nontraditional students?
Because a lot of us see
a lot of those nontraditional students
in community collages.
But we're also worried about the ones
that we're not seeing yet
who maybe in danger of losing their job.
Or pushed out a little early
because they needed AI (indistinct).
And I'm wondering if any of you are thinking about that
or working with that in the space that (indistinct).
- I know I've centered most of my comments today on the work
that we're doing with higher ed and career
or higher ed systems and K-12 systems.
But we have, you know, a whole arm of our organization
that does just that.
So we work with workforce development organizations,
workforce boards to make sure that folks
either who are later in life learners
or thinking about, okay, "How do my skills stay evergreen
as you know, I feel like the ground
is shifting underneath me?
How can I make sure that I'll have a job in five years,
like candidly."
So we work a lot with workforce development partners,
also continuous learning partners
within the education systems and also directly
within employers and enterprises to make sure
that their employees are upskilling continuously
to continue to meet their business objectives.
So I talked a little bit less about that,
but I'm happy to if you have questions after.
- Yeah, I mean I'll be like directly honest
like we haven't done much work with unconventional learners.
Kind of, in this vein, very differentiated,
but also something that I think is also
like a group that's considered unconventional learners
or like parents of students as well.
This is a big anxiety that we hear from adults
who have younger kids in the education system about,
"I don't know what advice to even give my kid nowadays.
They're like wondering about what careers they're exploring.
I don't know what to tell them."
Like parents themselves are feeling insecure
about their own ability to be a mentor to their own kids.
And in work with K-12 systems
and in partnering with other organizations like museums,
local libraries and organizations like afterschool programs.
These are organizations that are very, very, very plugged
into local communities
and probably know the needs of local communities
more than I as a national nonprofit might know.
And so partnering with these local community organizations
in order to help them embed programs for themselves,
for parents, for non-traditional learners, for students
that are going in through afterschool programming
or daycare, like making sure that those programs
are alive and well is really important as well.
The work that I'm doing is making sure that funding
for those kinds of programming doesn't stop
because a lot of what you're talking about
needs to be extremely community led.
A lot of learning spaces in communities are dying
and like the resources going to libraries and museums
and afterschool programs are not as strong
as they once were, as they were 10 years ago.
And so making sure that we're actually
not only giving funding but giving expertise
and giving resources to these kinds of communities
are things that I'm trying to do more of.
- Yeah, I think it's really important
to bring non-traditional students into focus
and we're having this conversation
'cause it's easy to get caught up in just, you know,
the next generation of learners.
But yeah, I appreciate that point.
While our work focuses on serving Gen Z,
specifically what we've done over the past year
with the community colleges has touched
some of the adult learners who are in that system
and some of the other non-traditional students.
So all of that to say, you know, our work is meant
to be applicable to them as well.
It's really thinking about just folks broadly
who are transitioning from learning into employment.
But I think that there needs to be more work done
on the specific challenges that non-traditional students
might be facing.
I don't think we're necessarily right now
that the best folks to do that,
but I think one of the big things I'm seeing is that,
you know, like the half life of skills is just decreasing
because whatever like technical, for example,
skills you develop right now,
they're just not necessarily going to be as relevant
or applicable in six months as they used to be.
And so thinking about what does it look like
to foster lifelong learning and adaptability is core skills,
that's gonna be really important.
So yeah, to sum that up,
our work does touch those groups,
but I really, really do think more
in depth work needs to be done there.
- Any other questions?
- Got one - Yes.
- This one may be for you, Christian.
You mentioned betting and literacy curriculums (indistinct)
on giving students or instructors something else to do.
Do you have any examples
of where you see that work really well?
- Yeah, I mean there's like maybe three different layers
to this that I talk about.
First is maybe the legislative layer
about in California we have both CTE coursework
that is funded through the states and HQIM,
which are like the high quality instructional materials
that are recommended by the state to education systems.
So like what do those recommendation structures look like
and how can they be updated?
That's a legislative trigger that needs to happen.
In practice, I think there's maybe one example
that's more relevant to this K-12
and one example is more relevant to community colleges.
So I'm gonna lean towards a community college example.
CTE coursework is actually
a really interesting system in California.
It's a pretty good example of a program
that is a direct collaboration between K-12 systems,
county offices, ROPs, and community colleges.
And a lot of times community colleges are the anchor point
for a lot of CTE programming work
that happens in different communities.
These CTE programs are oftentimes very, very slow to update,
especially if these are designed to be career
and technical education programs.
Careers are shifting so quickly
and CTE program delivery models are not shifting
as quickly to meet that need.
A really good example I'll highlight out
of the CTE programming work is the cybersecurity,
like CTE pathway that California has in place.
That program was developed back in 2012.
Technically that curriculum has not been updated since 2012.
And so if you are in any way maybe have an inclination
that 2012 cybersecurity curriculum is relevant
to today's workforce, there's probably a lot of problems
that that exist there.
But there have been a lot of individual ROPs
or community colleges in which the actual the faculty staff
have taken upon themselves to update
that coursework on their own.
And AI has been a very big disruptor,
especially in the cybersecurity space.
I would highlight the work that's happening out
of the South Orange County, ROP in collaboration
with Fullerton College and Cypress College, I believe.
They updated their cybersecurity pathway program
fully independently, separate from what
the curriculum that the state has given them.
And I think it's a very, very good update.
And it's a really good example of how
to embed AI literacy work in a career pathway program
that is not necessarily has to do with AI,
but AI affects greatly.
And I think cybersecurity is an example of that.
I would also look towards the arts.
There have been a lot of arts content
that have been updated in the past several years that...
Because arts is another space in which AI
has been a huge disruptor,
especially graphic and digital arts.
I'd look at the way that the arts courses
are updating their work for AI literacy work
'cause it does combine the combination of what is AI,
how does big data contribute to bias
and hallucination from AI,
down to individual tech-focused skills of using AI tools
in that work field.
I think those are two examples
that come to mind immediately for me.
- We've come to the end of our presentation.
I wanna do a quick thank you for the attendees
and thank you to Tara, Christian, and Summer
for their time and energy.
(audience clapping)
- Thanks guys. (people chattering)